WEIWEI JIANG

Software Developer

WESTERVILLE, OH | 614 900 2891 | WEIWEI.JIANG20@GMAIL.COM LINKEDIN: www.linkedin.com/in/wei-wei-jiang | GITHUB: https://github.com/Weiwei-20 PORTFOLIO: https://weiwei-20.github.io

PERSONAL PROFILE:

Software developer with a background in business and graphic design, focused on bringing people and technology together. Committed to providing solutions with a customer perspective. Effective strategist, able to quickly to changing priorities. Dedicate to reaching goals by utilizing my past professional experience.

SKILLS & ABILITIES:

- JavaScript
- MVC
- HTML
- CSS
- Flexbox
- Grid
- JSON
- Restful APIs
- Java
- Spring
- Hibernate
- JPA
- TDD
- Agile (Scrum)
- Thymeleaf

- Single Page
- Applications (SPAs)
- Responsive Design /
- Mobile
- Object Oriented
- Programming (OOP)
- Structured Query
- Language (SQL)
- Relational Databases
- VS Code
- IntelliJ
- Source Control / Git
- Kanban board
- Pair Programming

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND:

WE CAN CODE IT - Current

Otterbein University - May 2015

Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.)

Dalian University - June 2006

Bachelor's Degree, Graphic Design

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Software Development Student

We Can Code IT, January 2021 - Current

Planned, designed, and developed professionally programmed applications in collaborative team-based and independent settings.

Record Collection: Single page application for albums and songs.

JavaScript • HTML • CSS • Java • RESTful API • JSON • DOM • OOP • IntelliJ • VS Code • Git • GitHub • Kanban board • Pair Programming

Donut Maker: A clicker game was inspired by Cookie Clicker.

JavaScript • HTML • CSS • VS Code • Git • GitHub

Phone Review Website: A dynamic phone review website.

Java • HTML • CSS • Spring • Thymeleaf • VS Code • IntelliJ • Git • GitHub • OOP

Bootcamp Blog: A dynamic blog website.

Java • HTML • CSS • Spring • Thymeleaf • OOP • TDD • VS Code • IntelliJ • Git • GitHub

Professional Portfolio: A portfolio showcases my work and experience.

HTML • CSS • VSCode • Git • GitHub

Virtual Pet: Tamagotchi style console application.

Java • IntelliJ • Git • Github • GitBash • TDD • OOP

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Local Childcare Consultant (Part-Time)

Cultural Care Au Pair, Novermber 2017 - Current

- Provide year-round support for an average of 15 au pairs and host families.
- Screen and interview host families.
- Organize au pair monthly meetings and 2 host family day events each year.

Assistant Manager

Epoch LLC, April 2015 - April 2017

- Managed daily office administrative activities, which included performance evaluation and hiring new talent.
- Executed a new handbag production line from plan, design, sample, production, shipment, to the online website.
- Collaborated with Chinese and American teams, manufacturers, and delivery
- Visited factories in China, and maintain partnerships with suppliers.
- Represented brand at U.S. Travel Good Show, MAGIC show, and attended Canton Fair in China.
- Analyzed trends and inventory levels, and reorder products to replenish stock.
- Set-up and provided oversight for a +10,000 square foot warehouse.

Graphic Designer

Jisitang Design Company, June 2006 - January 2008

- Designed corporate visual identification system(CVIS), including logos, brochures, magazines, product packages, and posters.
- Communicated with clients, designed promotional graphic images.